<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jørund writes about IT</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jørund writes about IT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:02:16 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Microsoft 365 licensing. Part 1 - License basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:02:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licensing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year. You have one month before the yearly license numbers are due to be delivered to Microsoft. The questions have started pouring in. Can we make any savings? Are we utilizing all the features we have purchased? Do we have enough licenses for all our workloads? Are we even compliant?
This guide focuses on the things I consider to be the most important when designing your license strategy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Jørund Dahl, and I work at KONE in Finland as Platform Manager in the Digital Workplace Platforms team. I have a broad background from IT infrastructure, mostly focused on end user computing, security, identity and Microsoft 365.
Most of my work experience has been in large global companies, which poses many unique challenges when business requirements meets technology.
I enjoy following implementation projects from start to finish. Translating business requirements to projects, architectural design proces, technical implementation and hopefully a lot of automation / scripting in between.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
