<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jørund writes about IT</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jørund writes about IT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:36:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entra ID - Add permissions to Managed Identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/permissionsmanagedidentity/addpermissionstomanagedidentity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:36:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/permissionsmanagedidentity/addpermissionstomanagedidentity/</guid>
      <description>Adding permissions to Managed Identities in Entra ID is annoyingly complicated. To make the job easier for myself I made this short script to allow me to easily search through the permissions in my tenant and add it to the managed identity.
Connect-MgGraph -Scope Directory.Read.All, AppRoleAssignment.ReadWrite.All, Application.Read.All # Object ID of the managed identity, NOT application ID! $servicePrincipalId = &amp;#34;00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000&amp;#34; # Get all service principals in tenant $allServicePrincipal = Get-MgServicePrincipal -All $roles = $allServicePrincipal | ForEach-Object { foreach($r in $_.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entra ID application permission report with usage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/appconsentreport/appconsentreportwithsignins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 21:53:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/appconsentreport/appconsentreportwithsignins/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise applications and app registrations are two of the most dangerous things in Entra ID if managed incorrectly. They grant access to your data and resources, and if compromised, can lead to data breaches and other security incidents. Do you have control over all permissions granted over the course of your tenants lifetime? When was the last time you deleted stale permissions?
Application permission report My collegue Sridhar linked me a PowerShell module called MSIdentity Tools, which contains a command called Export-MsIdAppConsentGrantReport.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Advanced versioning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/versioning/sharepointadvancedversioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 19:59:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/versioning/sharepointadvancedversioning/</guid>
      <description>Is your company paying for extra SharePoint storage? Would you like not to?
What is it? SharePoint and OneDrive automatically saves major or minor versions as you work, so there is a history of changes that you can access and revert to if needed. Microsoft recently started rolling out general availability of feature ID 145802: &amp;ldquo;SharePoint: Improvements for document library version history limits&amp;rdquo;. In simpler terms this means we now have an automatic way of thinning out the version history of files and documents in SharePoint Online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Microsoft 365 licensing. Part 3 - Data retrieval and report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licenseoptimizationautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 19:00:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licenseoptimizationautomation/</guid>
      <description>The license profiles and strategy is clear. We understand what are the data sources to base our decisions on. Now we want to combine it all together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Microsoft 365 licensing. Part 2 - Data driven license optimization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licenseoptimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 22:40:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licenseoptimize/</guid>
      <description>This article will dive into license optimization. Which reports and measurements are available to us, and what are the important metrics to guide the decision on which license package a user needs? Ultimately, we want to use this information to reduce cost, but it can also help us to discover if we are uncompliant according to the license contract.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I recommend reading through part 1 of this series to get a brief understanding of license profiles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Microsoft 365 licensing. Part 1 - License basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:02:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/posts/microsoft365licensing/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year. You have one month before the yearly license numbers are due to be delivered to Microsoft. The questions have started pouring in. Can we make any savings? Are we utilizing all the features we have purchased? Do we have enough licenses for all our workloads? Are we even compliant?
This guide focuses on the things I consider to be the most important when designing your license strategy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jrndblog/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Jørund Dahl, and I work at KONE in Finland as Principal Platform Architect in the Digital Workplace Platforms team. I have a broad background from IT infrastructure, mostly focused on end user computing, security, identity and Microsoft 365.
Most of my work experience has been in large global companies, which poses many unique challenges when business requirements meets technology.
I enjoy following implementation projects from start to finish.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
